Then the next part what we want to do is we want to
在下个部分
be able to pull the movies that are most like that particular movie.
我们想要提取与特定电影最相似的电影
So what's the case here is that we have this dot_prod_movies,
这里有一个 dot_prod_movies 它是一个矩阵
which is a matrix where each row is associated with a particular movie,
每行代表一部电影
and each column is then associated with a movie as well.
每列也代表一部电影
Then the number in a particular cell
单元格中的数字
tells us how related those two movies are with each other.
表示两部电影之间的关系
So this three is a measure of
这个 3 表示
the relationship between the first movie and the second movie,
第一部电影与第二部电影之间的关系
and this three is the relationship between the first movie and the third movie.
这个 3 表示第一部电影与第三部电影之间的关系
This one is the relationship between the first movie and the fourth movie.
这个 1 表示第一部电影与第四部电影之间的关系
However, because we took the dot product of these NP arrays,
但是 因为我们计算的是这些 NamPy 数组的点积
we don't actually have the movie index associated with them.
所以不知道这些电影的索引
So what we're doing in this part is we're going to use this NP where to
在这里 我们将使用 np.where()
figure out which row that movie will exist in.
查找这部电影在哪一行
So the nice part is these movies only show up once.
好处在于 这些电影只出现了一次
The order shouldn't have changed by taking the dot product.
计算点积不会改变它们的顺序
So we can index into the array in the right spot by essentially pulling this value.
我们可以通过提取该值判断索引位置
So if we index into it once, we get an array,
如果传入索引一次 我们将获得一个数组
but actually I just want the number.
但是我只需这个数字
So I'm going to index into that one more time.
所以我将再传入索引一次
So this gives me which spot the 10th movie ID should fall in in my matrix.
得出第 10 个 movie_id 将在该矩阵里的位置
So which row or column, either way.
即哪行或哪列
So I'm just going to call this movie_index.
称为 movie_idx
In order to find the most similar movie,
为了查找最相似的电影
we want to find where the maximum value is.
我们需要找到最大值在哪
So the way that I decided to do that was by taking the movie_index,
我将传入 movie_idx
and I'm going to say, "Where is the value equal to max?"
并询问“哪里的值等于最大值”
So this part here is going to return an array.
这部分将返回一个数组
We store this into movie, and we run this.
将这个存储到 movie_idx 中 并运行这个
The idea is that this gives me the array associated with that particular movie.
这样就会获得与该电影相关的数组
If we take where that's the maximum,
如果调用 np.max()
so basically just this same thing, and we find that,
这里也是这部分代码
then this can get all of the places where the movies are most similar.
结果会得出最相似的电影所在的位置
So the very most similar.
即最为相似的电影
One of those movies will always be the movie itself,
其中一个电影始终是电影本身
but then the others will be other movies
其他电影将是
who basically shared the exact same content features,
具有完全相同的内容特征的电影
they were in the same year,
它们的年份相同
and they shared the same genres.
并且类型一样
Let's just run this really quick just to see what it gives us back.
快速运行下这行代码 看看返回什么结果
So basically, for this particular movie index,
对于这个 movie_idx
there are six movies that have the exact same content features.
有 6 部电影的内容特征完全一样
What I really want is just that array.
我只需这个数组
So if we just index into it once,
如果传入索引一次
we can get just that array,
我们将获得该数组
which is what I actually want. So I want that array.
这正是我想要的结果我想要该数组
I'm just going to call this similar_movies.
将这个称为 similar_movies
Actually, these are the indices.
实际上这些是索引
So I'm going to call this similar_indices.
所以我将称之为 similar_idxs
Then similar movies, if we go into the movies data frame,
然后是 similar_movies
and we pull the IDs,
我们从 movies DataFrame 中提取 ID
so we now have this array that's the indices,
现在获得了这个索引数组
and we can go back in and pull just the movie titles that we want.
我们可以从中提取想要的片名
So this part here is going into the original movies data frame,
这部分从原始的 movies DataFrame 中
and pulling those rows,
提取这些行
and then this is saying, "Just give me the movie column back.
这部分表示仅返回 movie 列
I don't want anything else,
我不想要其他部分
and then just give me that as a NumPy array." You can try this out.
并返回为 NumPy 数组尝试一下这部分代码
So if I have find_similar_movies to movie eight,
find_similar_movies(8)
here basically the movie title is associated with that.
这些是与电影 8 相关的电影片名
Or if I have movie 10, here are the movies
看看电影 10
that are most similar in terms of content to that movie.
这些是与该电影内容最相似的其他电影
If we do one of these other ones, like 91,
再看看 91
these are the movies that are most similar to movie 91.
这些是与电影 91 最相似的电影